<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Traveler's Guide to Elysia</name>
		<description>Homebrew content for Aurora Builder.</description>
		<author>Michael</author>
		<update version="0.1.1">
			<file name="race-emperor-hamster.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelclements2526/TGtE/refs/heads/master/tgte/race-emperor-hamster.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Race: Emperor Hamster     -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Emperor Hamster" type="Race" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACE_EMPEROR_HAMSTER">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">"The small creature squeaked in anger at me, as I had clearly chosen my words poorly, describing the creature as cute. As it squeaked and pointed at me, the ground seemed to begin to come alive, as hundreds of what appeared to be smaller versions of the hamster swarmed me, and crawled onto me. I'm lucky to be alive." — <i>Journal entry of Ven Gliy</i></p>

			<h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
			<p>Emperor hamsters resemble giant hamsters that stand upright on their hind legs, their posture and expressions carrying a strangely regal authority.</p>

			<h4>HISTORY</h4>
			<p>The first emperor hamster was a complete mistake—an attempted experiment to splice human and dwarven traits. Instead, something else emerged: a towering hamster with the presence of a monarch and the inexplicable loyalty of lesser hamsters. The mutation spread. Now emperor hamsters appear in scattered populations, sometimes as anomalies, sometimes as omens.</p>

			<h4>SOCIETY</h4>
			<p>Among humanoids, emperor hamsters are either mocked as absurdities or elevated as living symbols—treated like nobles, mascots, or “chosen” rulers. Among hamsterkind, they are something closer to divinity: a supreme creature whose will the swarm obeys.</p>

			<h4>EMPEROR HAMSTER NAMES</h4>
			<p>Emperor hamsters tend to adopt names of great rulers and legendary figures—whether or not they hold any power beyond attitude.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Male Names.</i></b> Agamemnon, Alexandros, Apollonios, Ariston, Demetrios, Diokles, Epiktetos, Herakleides, Nikias, Philon, Theophilos</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Female Names.</i></b> Aphrodisia, Athenais, Demetria, Eirene, Euphrosyne, Phile, Philia, Philoumente, Rhene, Sostrate</p>

			<h4>EMPEROR HAMSTER TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your emperor hamster character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Age.</span> Emperor hamsters mature as fast as humans do and live for about 200 years.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Emperor hamsters are often chaotic, grasping for status and influence wherever they can.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Size.</span> Emperor hamsters are 3 to 4 feet tall. Your size is Small.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your walking speed is 25 feet. You also have a burrowing speed of 15 feet.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Darkvision.</span> You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Furball.</span> As a bonus action, you roll your body into a ball, entering a rolling state. While rolling, your speed doubles, and you can move through the space of Medium and smaller creatures without treating it as difficult terrain. When you move through a creature’s space, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take bludgeoning damage and fall prone (details in trait).<br/>
				<span class="feature">Keen Nose, Little Eyes.</span> You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell, but disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Bite.</span> Your bite is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. On a hit, it deals piercing damage (details in trait).<br/>
				<span class="feature">Hamsters Ruling.</span> Once per day, you can call an army of hamsters to your side (details in trait).<br/>
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and Hamster-Squeak.<br/>
			</p>

			<h4>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h4>
			<p>When creating an emperor hamster character, the Noble background is a fitting starting point—whether or not you’re actually welcome in court.</p>
		</description>

		<sheet display="false"/>

		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Agamemnon, Alexandros, Apollonios, Ariston, Demetrios, Diokles, Epiktetos, Herakleides, Nikias, Philon, Theophilos</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Aphrodisia, Athenais, Demetria, Eirene, Euphrosyne, Phile, Philia, Philoumente, Rhene, Sostrate</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>

			<!-- Printer-safe defaults (random tables stay in the lore, not in setters) -->
			<set name="height">3'0"</set>
			<set name="weight">30 lb.</set>
		</setters>

		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2"/>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1"/>

			<stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="innate speed:burrow" value="15" bonus="base"/>

			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_ELYSIA_LANGUAGE_HAMSTER_SQUEAK" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_FURBALL" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_KEEN_NOSE_LITTLE_EYES" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_BITE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_HAMSTERS_RULING" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Language: Hamster-Squeak  -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Hamster-Squeak" type="Language" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_LANGUAGE_HAMSTER_SQUEAK">
		<description>
			<p>Hamster-Squeak is the language shared by hamsterkind, built from squeaks, chirps, and subtle nose twitches. Other creatures can learn it, but it often takes years of exposure to pick up its nuance.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Squeaks, chirps, and nose-twitch nuance shared by hamsterkind.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Racial Traits             -->
	<!-- ========================= -->

	<element name="Furball" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_FURBALL">
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you roll your body into a ball, entering a rolling state.</p>
			<p>While rolling, your speed doubles, and you can move through the space of Medium and smaller creatures without treating it as difficult terrain.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you move through a creature’s space, it must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC = {{emperor-hamster:furball:dc}}). On a failed save, it takes 2d4 + your Strength modifier bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, it takes no damage and isn’t knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent">The rolling state ends if you choose to end it (no action required) or if you are incapacitated.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Enter rolling state: speed doubles; move through Medium or smaller creatures. When you pass through a creature’s space, it saves (DC {{emperor-hamster:furball:dc}} Dex) or takes 2d4+STR bludgeoning and falls prone.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="emperor-hamster:furball:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="emperor-hamster:furball:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="emperor-hamster:furball:dc" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Keen Nose, Little Eyes" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_KEEN_NOSE_LITTLE_EYES">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell, but disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Advantage on Perception (smell). Disadvantage on Perception (sight).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_BITE">
		<description>
			<p>Your bite is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Natural weapon: Bite. On a hit, deal 1d4+STR piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Hamsters Ruling" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPEROR_HAMSTER_HAMSTERS_RULING">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, once per day, you can call upon an army of hamsters. This army appears in spaces you choose within 30 feet of you, and it follows your commands for the duration.</p>
			<p class="indent">Use the <i>Swarm of Rats</i> stat block in the Monster Manual as a reference for the army’s mechanics and baseline.</p>
			<p class="indent">At levels 5, 10, 15, and 20, the swarm “doubles in size” (DM-facing narrative scaling), and the maximum duration increases by 1 hour each time it grows (2 hours at 5th, 3 hours at 10th, 4 hours at 15th, 5 hours at 20th).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Day">
			<description>Summon an army of hamsters (use Swarm of Rats as reference). Duration 1 hour; +1 hour at levels 5/10/15/20. “Doubles in size” at 5/10/15/20 (DM scaling).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
