<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Traveler's Guide to Elysia</name>
		<description>Homebrew content for Aurora Builder.</description>
		<author>Michael</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="race-elysian-lunarian.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Race: Lunarian             -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunarian" type="Race" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACE_LUNARIAN">
		<description>
			<h4>LUNARIANS</h4>
			<p>Lunarians are an extraordinarily rare people believed to be descendants of the Moon itself—or shaped so completely by lunar influence that the distinction no longer matters. Deeply attuned to magic and the night sky, Lunarians perceive arcane forces instinctively, reacting to spells and supernatural phenomena in ways that often defy mortal logic.</p>
			<p>To most folk, the Moon is distant and mute. To Lunarians, it is intimate: a presence that watches, measures, and answers. Their emotions tend to run bright beneath moonlight, and their sense of time is subtly misaligned with the mortal world—days are easy to count, but decades feel like seasons.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em>“Every lunarian is born with an obsession. Some chart stars. Some count footsteps. Some refuse to let a single thought end where it began.”</em></p>

			<h4>CHILDREN OF MOONLIGHT</h4>
			<p>Lunarians are not a people you “find” so much as you <em>notice</em>. A village may go a lifetime with none, then remember one forever: the child whose eyes reflected a pale ring even in darkness; the traveler who always knew when a spell was forming; the friend who spoke of the night sky like it was a map of personal history.</p>
			<p>Some tales insist Lunarians are born when moonlight strikes a newborn’s skin for the first time. Others claim they are shaped by prolonged exposure to lunar power—sleeping too many nights beneath a silvered sky, surviving a ritual gone wrong, or carrying a family curse that is not quite a curse. However it happens, the result is the same: the Moon leaves a signature on the soul.</p>

			<h4>PURE &amp; LUNAR-TOUCHED</h4>
			<p>Two forms of Lunarians exist: <strong>Pure Lunarians</strong>, whose bodies fully reflect their lunar heritage, and <strong>Lunar-Touched</strong>, members of other ancestries altered by the Moon’s influence.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Pure Lunarians</strong> often exhibit rabbit-like ears and a small, rounded scut. Their features may appear soft or pale, and their irises can seem dusted with glitter or starlight when interacting with magic. They mature at a human rate but commonly live between 800 and 1,000 years.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Lunar-Touched</strong> resemble their origin ancestry—human, elf, dwarf, tiefling, and so on—with only subtle lunar reactions and an extended lifespan marking them as lunar. Many Lunar-Touched live roughly twice as long as members of their origin ancestry, and some report that their emotions feel “louder” beneath open night sky.</p>

			<h4>LUNAR REACTIONS</h4>
			<p>All Lunarians—Pure and Lunar-Touched alike—exhibit lunar reactions. These are not always constant, but they are unmistakable when they appear. The Moon does not merely shine on them; it <em>answers</em>.</p>
			<p>When using <strong>Lunar Glow</strong>, casting spells, or standing beneath true moonlight, subtle signs may surface:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Hair emitting a faint glow</li>
				<li>Arcane markings along the skin becoming visible</li>
				<li>Eyes reflecting pale lunar light</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">Among Lunarians, these signs are treated as normal as breathing. Among others, they are often mistaken for omens.</p>

			<h4>TEMPERAMENT &amp; OBSESSION</h4>
			<p>Pure Lunarians invariably develop an obsession—an idea, object, practice, belief, or fixation that shapes their behavior for years or centuries. This is widely understood as a natural consequence of lunar influence rather than madness. The Moon narrows the mind the way a lens narrows light: not to reduce it, but to concentrate it until it burns.</p>
			<p>If you want to choose randomly, roll a d12 on the table below.</p>
			<h5>OBSESSION (D12)</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d12</td><td>Obsession</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Justice</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Animals</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Plants</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>The Sea &amp; Tides</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Stars &amp; Constellations</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Music</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Dreams &amp; Sleep</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Knowledge</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Protection</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Crafting</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11</td><td>Secrets</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12</td><td>Freedom</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p>Lunar-Touched Lunarians often retain the psychology of their origin ancestry, but many report heightened intuition, restlessness, or emotional intensity under the night sky.</p>

			<h4>LUNARIAN NAMES</h4>
			<p>Most Lunarians take names from the cultures that raise them. However, Pure Lunarians in particular often adopt “moon-names”—titles drawn from the names of moons and celestial bodies—as a quiet nod to their origin. These names are not claims of divinity; they are reminders. To a Lunarian, a moon-name is a promise to remain in motion, to keep returning, and to never be entirely understood at first glance.</p>

			<h4>LUNARIAN TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your Lunarian character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your ability score increases are determined by your Lunarian Origin.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Size.</span> Your size is Medium.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your walking speed is 35 feet.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Age.</span> Lunarians mature at a rate similar to humans, but age far more slowly.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Arcane Training.</span> You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill. In addition, you gain proficiency in either Perception or Performance (your choice).<br/>
				<span class="feature">Lunar Perception.</span> You have blindsight out to a range of 20 feet.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Lunar Glow.</span> Once per short rest, as a bonus action, you emit moonlight in a 5-foot radius of bright light, with dim light for an additional 10 feet. This light lasts for 10 minutes or until you dismiss it (no action required).<br/>
				<span class="feature">Arcane Sensitivity.</span> Once per long rest, when you are required to make a saving throw against a spell, you can choose to gain advantage on that saving throw. You can use this trait even if you cannot see the source of the spell. You must choose to use this trait before rolling.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Lunar Reactions.</span> When using Lunar Glow, casting spells, or standing beneath moonlight, subtle signs may appear: hair emitting a faint glow; arcane markings along the skin becoming visible; eyes reflecting pale lunar light.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Lunarian Origin.</span> Choose Pure Lunarian or Lunar-Touched. Your origin determines your ability score increases and grants additional traits.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>

		<sheet display="false" />

		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Ganymede, Titan, Iapetus, Hyperion, Janus, Oberon, Triton, Proteus, Enceladus, Mimas, Prometheus, Epimetheus, Deimos, Phobos</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Io, Europa, Callisto, Amalthea, Thebe, Metis, Adrastea, Himalia, Elara, Pasiphae, Sinope, Lysithea, Carme, Ananke, Leda, Rhea, Dione, Tethys, Phoebe, Miranda, Ariel, Umbriel, Titania</set>
			<set name="names" type="surname">Moonwake, Silvervein, Nightglass, Starweft, Palecrest, Luneshard, Dawnglint, Eclipseborne, Gloamharbor, Astralwyn, Skysigil, Voidpetal</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>

			<!-- Printer-mode: no dice modifiers in setters -->
			<set name="height">4'10"</set>
			<set name="weight">110 lb.</set>
		</setters>

		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="35" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<select type="Language" name="Languages (Lunarian)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ARCANE_TRAINING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_GLOW" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ARCANE_SENSITIVITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_REACTIONS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Vision: Blindsight (20 ft) -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Blindsight (20 ft)" type="Vision" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_VISION_BLINDSIGHT_20">
		<description><p>You have blindsight out to a range of 20 feet.</p></description>
		<sheet><description>Blindsight 20 ft.</description></sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="vision:blindsight" value="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Arcane Training            -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Arcane Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ARCANE_TRAINING">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill. In addition, you gain proficiency in either Perception or Performance (your choice).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Proficiency: Arcana. Also gain proficiency in either Perception or Performance.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Arcane Training Skill" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Lunar Perception           -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunar Perception" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_PERCEPTION">
		<description>
			<p>You possess heightened awareness shaped by lunar and arcane influence.</p>
			<p>You have blindsight out to a range of 20 feet. Within this range, you perceive creatures and objects through subtle shifts in magic, light, and presence rather than sight alone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet><description>Blindsight 20 ft.</description></sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_ELYSIA_VISION_BLINDSIGHT_20" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Lunar Glow                 -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunar Glow" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_GLOW">
		<description>
			<p>Once per short rest, as a bonus action, you emit moonlight in a 5-foot radius of bright light, with dim light for an additional 10 feet.</p>
			<p>This light lasts for 10 minutes or until you dismiss it (no action required).</p>
			<p class="indent">This glow may cause your hair, eyes, or lunar markings to visibly shimmer.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>Emit moonlight for 10 minutes: 5 ft bright light, +10 ft dim light. Dismiss it (no action).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Arcane Sensitivity         -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Arcane Sensitivity" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ARCANE_SENSITIVITY">
		<description>
			<p>Once per long rest, when you are required to make a saving throw against a spell, you can choose to gain advantage on that saving throw. You can use this trait even if you cannot see the source of the spell.</p>
			<p>You must choose to use this trait before rolling.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you make a saving throw against a spell, you can gain advantage (choose before rolling).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Lunar Reactions (cosmetic) -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunar Reactions" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_REACTIONS">
		<description>
			<p>When using Lunar Glow, casting spells, or standing beneath moonlight, subtle signs may appear: hair emitting a faint glow, arcane markings becoming visible, eyes reflecting pale lunar light.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Cosmetic: hair/eyes/markings may shimmer under moonlight or when using magic.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Lunarian Origin (selector) -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunarian Origin" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN">
		<description>
			<p>Choose one of the following origins at character creation: Pure Lunarian or Lunar-Touched.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Choose your origin: Pure Lunarian or Lunar-Touched.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Lunarian Origin" supports="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN_PURE|ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN_TOUCHED" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Origin: Pure Lunarian      -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Pure Lunarian" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN_PURE">
		<description>
			<p>Pure Lunarians are fully shaped by lunar influence, both physically and spiritually.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Increase one of your Wisdom, Intelligence, or Charisma scores by 2, and increase your Dexterity score by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Lunar Melody.</span> When you spend Hit Dice to regain hit points during a short rest, you regain the maximum number of hit points possible for each Hit Die spent.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Trance of the Moon.</span> In addition, you require only 6 hours to complete a long rest.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Pure Lunarian">
			<description>ASI: +2 (Wis/Int/Cha), +1 Dex. Maximize Hit Dice healing on short rests. Long rests require only 6 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_CHOICE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_MELODY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Pure Lunarian Ability Score Increase" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_CHOICE">
		<description><p>Increase one of your Wisdom, Intelligence, or Charisma scores by 2.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Increase one of Wisdom, Intelligence, or Charisma by 2.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Pure Lunarian Ability Score Increase (+2)" supports="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_WIS|ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_INT|ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_CHA" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Pure Lunarian ASI (+2 Wisdom)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_WIS">
		<description><p>Your Wisdom score increases by 2.</p></description>
		<sheet alt="ASI (+2 Wisdom)"><description>Wisdom +2.</description></sheet>
		<rules><stat name="wisdom" value="2" /></rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Pure Lunarian ASI (+2 Intelligence)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_INT">
		<description><p>Your Intelligence score increases by 2.</p></description>
		<sheet alt="ASI (+2 Intelligence)"><description>Intelligence +2.</description></sheet>
		<rules><stat name="intelligence" value="2" /></rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Pure Lunarian ASI (+2 Charisma)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_PURE_ASI_CHA">
		<description><p>Your Charisma score increases by 2.</p></description>
		<sheet alt="ASI (+2 Charisma)"><description>Charisma +2.</description></sheet>
		<rules><stat name="charisma" value="2" /></rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Lunar Melody" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_LUNAR_MELODY">
		<description>
			<p>When you spend Hit Dice to regain hit points during a short rest, you regain the maximum number of hit points possible for each Hit Die spent.</p>
			<p>In addition, you require only 6 hours to complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Maximize Hit Dice healing during short rests. You need only 6 hours for a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Origin: Lunar-Touched      -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Lunar-Touched" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ORIGIN_TOUCHED">
		<description>
			<p>Lunar-Touched Lunarians are members of other ancestries marked by prolonged exposure to lunar power.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Increase one ability score of your choice by 2, and increase a different ability score of your choice by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Ecliptic Surge.</span> Once per short rest, after you roll a d20 for an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw and determine the result, you can choose to add your proficiency bonus to the roll. This bonus is added in addition to any proficiency bonus already applied. You can use this trait after seeing the roll, but before the outcome is resolved.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Origin Ancestry.</span> Choose the ancestry you resemble (cosmetic).<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Lunar-Touched">
			<description>ASI: +2 any, +1 different any. Ecliptic Surge. Origin Ancestry (cosmetic).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase +2 (Lunar-Touched)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase +1 (Lunar-Touched)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ECLIPTIC_SURGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_ANCESTRY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Ecliptic Surge" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_ECLIPTIC_SURGE">
		<description>
			<p>Once per short rest, after you roll a d20 for an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw and determine the result, you can choose to add your proficiency bonus to the roll.</p>
			<p>This bonus is added in addition to any proficiency bonus already applied.</p>
			<p>You can use this trait after seeing the roll, but before the outcome is resolved.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>After you roll a d20 and see the result, you can add your proficiency bonus (before the outcome is resolved).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry (cosmetic) -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Origin Ancestry (Lunar-Touched)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_ANCESTRY">
		<description><p>If you are Lunar-Touched, choose the ancestry you resemble. This choice is cosmetic.</p></description>
		<sheet><description>Choose an origin ancestry (cosmetic).</description></sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Origin Ancestry (Cosmetic)" supports="Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Human" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_HUMAN">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Human"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Human.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Dwarf" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_DWARF">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Dwarf"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Dwarf.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Elf" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_ELF">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Elf"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Elf.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Halfling" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_HALFLING">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Halfling"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Halfling.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Gnome" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_GNOME">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Gnome"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Gnome.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Half-Elf" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_HALF_ELF">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Half-Elf"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Half-Elf.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Half-Orc" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_HALF_ORC">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Half-Orc"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Half-Orc.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Dragonborn" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_DRAGONBORN">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Dragonborn"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Dragonborn.</description></sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Origin Ancestry: Tiefling" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LUNARIAN_TOUCHED_ORIGIN_TIEFLING">
		<supports>Lunar-Touched Origin Ancestry</supports>
		<sheet alt="Tiefling"><description>Origin Ancestry (cosmetic): Tiefling.</description></sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
