<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Traveler's Guide to Elysia</name>
		<description>Homebrew content for Aurora Builder.</description>
		<author>Michael</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="race-living-wood.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Race: Living Wood         -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Living Wood" type="Race" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACE_LIVING_WOOD">
		<description>
			<h4>LIVING WOOD</h4>
			<p>Living Wood are sentient plantfolk deliberately created by druidic circles to serve as companions, assistants, and guardians of the natural world. Through ancient rites blending druidic magic with living timber, these beings are grown rather than born—shaped with emotions, cognition, and moral reasoning comparable to humanoids. This design is intentional. Living Wood are not tools, but caretakers meant to act with judgment in both peace and crisis.</p>
			<p>They are neither constructs nor mindless plants. Living Wood are alive, aware, and capable of choice—crafted to endure where others pass on.</p>

			<h4>PURPOSE &amp; TEMPERAMENT</h4>
			<p>Most Living Wood adhere to lawful philosophies, reflecting the circles that shaped them: consistency, responsibility, preservation. Their sense of law is rooted not in written codes, but in continuity and duty. Though often calm and patient, Living Wood are not emotionless. They experience attachment, pride, frustration, and grief—tempered by the understanding that nature unfolds across long spans of time.</p>
			<p class="indent">Many are treated by outsiders as if they were constructs: addressed by their “designations,” evaluated by utility, or assumed to be property. Most circles consider this misunderstanding both common and dangerous. A Living Wood that cannot choose is not a guardian—it is a liability.</p>

			<h4>NEW WOOD &amp; OLD WOOD</h4>
			<p>All Living Wood are created through ritual, but not all are created from the same timber.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>New Wood</strong> are formed from younger or more modest trees. They are typically Medium in size—more mobile, more adaptable, and more likely to travel beyond the grove.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong>Old Wood</strong> are created using ancient trees that, over the course of their long lives, have had extensive contact with magic—growing near ley lines, within druidic sanctuaries, or beneath places where the natural and arcane worlds overlap. This accumulated magic does not grant spellcasting; it condenses into density, presence, and endurance. Old Wood emerge Large, slower to move but difficult to displace.</p>

			<h4>LIVING WOOD TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your Living Wood character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Increase one ability score of your choice by 2, and increase a different ability score of your choice by 1.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Creature Type.</span> You are a Plant.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Size.</span> You are Medium or Large (your choice). Medium Living Wood are called New Wood; Large Living Wood are called Old Wood.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your walking speed is 30 feet if you are Medium. Your walking speed is 20 feet if you are Large.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Age.</span> Living Wood typically live between 100 and 150 years.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and Druidic.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Skill Proficiency.</span> You gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Survival, Animal Handling, Nature, or History.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Wooden Frame.</span> While you are not wearing armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Constitution modifier. You can still benefit from a shield.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Rooted Awareness.</span> While you are in contact with the ground, you have tremorsense out to a range of 30 feet.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Barkbound Resilience.</span> You have resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning damage.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Bark Harden.</span> When you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d8. You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus per long rest.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Rooted Constitution.</span> You gain a 1d4 bonus to Constitution saving throws.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Grasping Limbs.</span> When you successfully grapple a creature smaller than you, you can choose to restrain it instead. The restrained creature can use its action to attempt to escape, following the normal rules for ending a grapple.<br/>
				<span class="feature">Old Wood Reach.</span> If you are Large, your melee weapon attacks have their reach increased by 5 feet.<br/>
			</p>
		</description>

		<sheet display="false" />

		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Ashroot, Stonebark, Greenwake, Ironwood, Mossbound, Deepgrain, Thornreach, Oakfall, Reedmarch, Cinderbough, Birchward, Hollowstem, Sapveil, Brambleknit</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Ashroot, Stonebark, Greenwake, Ironwood, Mossbound, Deepgrain, Thornreach, Oakfall, Reedmarch, Cinderbough, Birchward, Hollowstem, Sapveil, Brambleknit</set>
			<set name="names" type="surname">of the Grove, of the Boundary, of the Old Ring, of the Green Oath, of Root and Stone, of the Quiet Vale</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>

			<set name="height" modifier="2d10">5'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">220 lb.</set>
		</setters>

		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BODY" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRUIDIC" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ASI" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_SKILL" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_WOODEN_FRAME" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ROOTED_AWARENESS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BARKBOUND_RESILIENCE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BARK_HARDEN" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ROOTED_CONSTITUTION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_GRASPING_LIMBS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- ASI: +2 and +1             -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Ability Score Increase (Living Wood)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ASI">
		<description>
			<p>Increase one ability score of your choice by 2, and increase a different ability score of your choice by 1.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Increase one ability score by 2 and a different ability score by 1.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase +2 (Living Wood)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase +1 (Living Wood)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Body choice: New/Old Wood  -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="New Wood / Old Wood" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BODY">
		<description>
			<p>Choose whether you are New Wood (Medium) or Old Wood (Large). This determines your size, speed, and reach.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Choose New Wood (Medium, 30 ft) or Old Wood (Large, 20 ft, reach +5 ft).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Living Wood Body" supports="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_NEW|ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_OLD" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="New Wood" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_NEW">
		<description>
			<p>You are New Wood, formed from younger or more modest trees.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your size is Medium, and your walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="New Wood">
			<description>Size: Medium. Speed: 30 ft.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Old Wood" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_OLD">
		<description>
			<p>You are Old Wood, created from an ancient tree long steeped in magic.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your size is Large, your walking speed is 20 feet, and your melee weapon attacks have their reach increased by 5 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Old Wood">
			<description>Size: Large. Speed: 20 ft. Melee weapon reach +5 ft.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="20" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_LARGE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_OLD_REACH" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Old Wood Reach" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_OLD_REACH">
		<description><p>If you are Large, your melee weapon attacks have their reach increased by 5 feet.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you are Large, your melee weapon attacks have their reach increased by 5 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Skill choice               -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Skill Proficiency (Living Wood)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_SKILL">
		<description><p>You gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Survival, Animal Handling, Nature, or History.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Choose one skill proficiency: Survival, Animal Handling, Nature, or History.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Living Wood Skill Proficiency" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Vision: Tremorsense (30)   -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Tremorsense (30 ft)" type="Vision" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_VISION_TREMORSENSE_30">
		<description><p>You have tremorsense out to a range of 30 feet.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Tremorsense 30 ft.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="vision:tremorsense" value="30" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Wooden Frame               -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Wooden Frame" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_WOODEN_FRAME">
		<description>
			<p>While you are not wearing armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Constitution modifier. You can still benefit from a shield.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While not wearing armor, your AC equals 10 + your Constitution modifier (shield allowed).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Rooted Awareness           -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Rooted Awareness" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ROOTED_AWARENESS">
		<description>
			<p>While you are in contact with the ground, you have tremorsense out to a range of 30 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While in contact with the ground, you have tremorsense 30 ft.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_ELYSIA_VISION_TREMORSENSE_30" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Barkbound Resilience       -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Barkbound Resilience" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BARKBOUND_RESILIENCE">
		<description><p>You have resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning damage.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Bark Harden (Reaction)     -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Bark Harden" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_BARK_HARDEN">
		<description>
			<p>When you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d8.</p>
			<p>You can use this trait a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus per long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>Reduce B/P/S damage by 1d8. Uses equal to your proficiency bonus per long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Rooted Constitution        -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Rooted Constitution" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_ROOTED_CONSTITUTION">
		<description><p>You gain a 1d4 bonus to Constitution saving throws.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Add 1d4 to Constitution saving throws.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- ========================= -->
	<!-- Grasping Limbs             -->
	<!-- ========================= -->
	<element name="Grasping Limbs" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_LIVING_WOOD_GRASPING_LIMBS">
		<description>
			<p>When you successfully grapple a creature smaller than you, you can choose to restrain it instead. The restrained creature can use its action to attempt to escape, following the normal rules for ending a grapple.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you grapple a creature smaller than you, you can restrain it instead (escape uses normal grapple rules).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
