<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <element name="Elysian Dragon-Kin" type="Race" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_RACE_DRAGON_KIN">
    <description>
      <p>Dragon-Kin are humanoids who carry draconic blood not as a distant echo, but as a living inheritance. Unlike dragonborn, whose lineage manifests uniformly, Dragon-Kin display their heritage in varied and personal ways—through antler-like horns, patches of shimmering scales, and tails that move with deliberate balance.</p>
      <p>Their draconic ancestry is ancient rather than immediate. At some point deep within their lineage, a dragon became bound to a mortal bloodline through means long lost to history. Once established, this inheritance does not fade or dilute over generations. A Dragon-Kin family remains draconic indefinitely, which is both the source of their power and the reason for their rarity.</p>
      <p>Though uncommon, Dragon-Kin often integrate seamlessly into the cultures they inhabit, identifying more with the societies that raised them than with any unified Dragon-Kin culture.</p>

      <h4>TRAITS</h4>
      <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Increase two different ability scores of your choice by 1.<br />
      <span class="feature">Size. </span>You are Medium.<br />
      <span class="feature">Speed. </span>Your walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
      <span class="feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic.<br />
      <span class="feature">Darkvision. </span>You have darkvision out to 30 feet. In addition, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.<br />
      <span class="feature">Draconic Will. </span>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.<br />
      <span class="feature">Cultural Adaptation. </span>You gain proficiency with one tool of your choice, or you learn one additional language of your choice.<br />
      <span class="feature">Draconic Insight. </span>You gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Perception, Nature, Survival, or Insight.<br />
      <span class="feature">Draconic Expression. </span>Choose one: Great Wings, Draconic Magic, or Great Horns.<br />
      <span class="feature">Draconic Color. </span>Choose one draconic color. This determines the damage type for Draconic Magic and any feature that references your draconic damage type.<br />
    </description>

    <sheet>
      <description>
        Darkvision 30 ft. Advantage on sight-based Perception checks.
        Advantage on saves vs charmed and frightened.
        Draconic Insight: choose two skills (Perception/Nature/Survival/Insight).
        Cultural Adaptation: one tool proficiency OR one extra language.
        Draconic Expression: Great Wings OR Draconic Magic OR Great Horns.
        Draconic Color: Ruby/ Sapphire/ Emerald/ Topaz/ Crystal/ Obsidian/ Amethyst.
      </description>
    </sheet>

    <rules>
      <stat name="speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />

      <!-- Skills are safe to grant/select -->
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_DRAGON_KIN_DRACONIC_INSIGHT" />

      <!-- Extra language is safe; tool selection is removed for now -->
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_DRAGON_KIN_CULTURAL_ADAPTATION_LANGUAGE_ONLY" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- Draconic Insight: choose 2 skills -->
  <element name="Draconic Insight" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_DRAGON_KIN_DRACONIC_INSIGHT">
    <description><p>You gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Perception, Nature, Survival, or Insight.</p></description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Draconic Insight (Skill 1)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Draconic Insight (Skill 2)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- Cultural Adaptation (safe mode): extra language only -->
  <element name="Cultural Adaptation (Language)" type="Racial Trait" source="Traveler's Guide to Elysia" id="ID_ELYSIA_TRAIT_DRAGON_KIN_CULTURAL_ADAPTATION_LANGUAGE_ONLY">
    <description><p>You learn one additional language of your choice.</p></description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Language" name="Cultural Adaptation — Extra Language" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="1" />
    </rules>
  </element>
</elements>